Two teams build systems separately, in fact,
even in different GCP projects,
and suddenly they need to talk to each other privately.
This is exactly where VPC peering is going to use.
Let's see how we can do that.
I'm in the console, and I have two projects.
One is hpc3 and another one is hpc2.
Earlier in the previous clip, we have added both of
these two projects to the shared VPC.
I've removed that and deleted all the instances so that these are clean now.
What we're going to do is we're going to create two different
networks in each of these projects, and then we're going to do
the VPC peering between them.
So for that, come down to the hpc2 and let's create one new VPC network.
Say here, Create VPC network.
I give the name as project‑2‑vpc.
Similarly, for the subnet, I'm going to give the name as project‑2‑vpc‑subnet.
In the IP range,
I'm going to select the IP range as 10.1.0.0, and I'm going to say Create.
Select the region as asia‑southeast1 and say Create.
Now on similar lines, go to the other project.
Here also, I go down to my VPC.
Here as well, I'm going to create one VPC network.
I'm going to call this as project‑3‑vpc.
On similar lines, I'm going to give the name as project‑3‑vpc‑subnet,
select the region as asia‑southeast1,
select the IP range as 10.2.0.0 and say Create.
Now both the project has their VPC.
Now it's time to create a VPC peering.
So I'm going back into the project 2, and I'm creating a VPC network peering.
In the VPC network peering, click on Create connection,
give the name as project2‑to‑3, that is the connection. Select the VPC network,
that is project‑2‑vpc, and where we want to do this peering into another project.
So I need another project ID.
So I come down here, copy the name of my project ID, say this,
and it will ask me to give the name of the VPC there.
Say Create.
Now this will create the peering from project 2 to project 3.
Now to check whether this is working or not,
I'm going to create two instances, one in each project.
So I come down here, Create instance.
Now while I'm going to create the instance,
I'm going to choose a specific network here under the Networking setting.
The network is project‑2‑vpc.
Second project, I'm using the project‑2‑vpc as my network and say Create.
I go to the project 3, and I'm going to create one instance here as well.
Create instance,
select the region. Under the Networking field, we're going to select
here the network as our project‑3‑vpc and say Create.
Now we have an instance in each of these projects,
and I want to connect project 2 to project 3 using the peering.
Now I have to just test so I can just come down here and say
SSH. We also need to create the VPC peering from project 3 to
project 2, so let's do that as well.
Say Create connection and give the name as peering‑project‑3‑to‑2.
Select the network and select the project ID.
Select the VPC name and say Create.
Now,
if I do the SSH from this project 2 and in the project
3, the VM IP address is 10.2.0.2.
So I can just say here,
ping 10.2.0.2, and see we are able to make a connection to
the project 3 instance from project 2, because we have done the VPC peering.
The network can now talk internally using private IP.